<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-24T13:09:13-07:00</updated><id>http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/</id><title>YYIMTT</title><subtitle>Write your site description here. It will be used as your sites meta description as well!</subtitle><entry><title>Trinket</title><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/07/24/trinket/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trinket" /><published>2016-07-24T05:23:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-07-24T05:23:00-07:00</updated><id>http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/07/24/trinket</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/07/24/trinket/">&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning in my Southeast Portland bed and immediately opened up my own Portland breakfast to-do list to see where I should go next. I settled with a place called Trinket on the corner of SE Lincoln and Cesar Chavez nestled between an independent bicycle shop and a hair salon. Trinket is only open until the early afternoon so I got the feeling that they knew what they were doing when it come to breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just after 10:30 I sat down in a creaky wooden chair at a table for one, greeted by a smile, a glass bottle of water and a steamy mug of coffee. The modest menu stared back at me, presenting me with the morning’s best problem. Approaching a menu like this with an open mind sets you up with the best chances for breakfast triumph. A quick debriefing with the waitress revealed that all of the meats serves at Trinket are made in house, quickly drawing me away the sweet waffle option or the avocado toast and toward a menu items featuring braised pork shoulder. I settled on the polenta plus a seasonal fruit plate and was not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about a half a cup of coffee the waitress delivered with my breakfast. A lagoon of polenta surrounded by sautéed kale and mushrooms topped with two over easy eggs. I quickly had to remind myself not to judge a book by its cover and dig in to what initially appeared to be a vegetarian dream.  Pulling back the veil of kale revealed an unexpected stash of fall-apart-tender pineapple braised pork shoulder. Jackpot.  Mopping up a bite of the egg, pork, kale and polenta created a perfectly balanced quartet of breakfast food. Any one of the components on their own made for a harsh bite. The pork was awfully salty, the kale was pretty bitter, and polenta was ordinary but together they made such sweet music. Surprisingly I was left wishing that I had a little less pork and a bit more polenta to even out the ratios of the dish. Creamy polenta balanced out the pork and kale while the eggs supplied a vital breakfast feeling.  Not to mention the fruit plate featuring the best the Pacific Northwest has to offer at this time of year, rounding out the entire dish. Kudos to Trinket for this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely a place I can see myself coming back to, which is high praise in my book. In a city with so many good breakfast options it only makes sense to go back to a place if it really offers something unique. The vibe at Trinket was anything but pretentious and their dedication to strictly breakfast and brunch garners a lot of respect from me. It’s much more valuable to do a few things very well as opposed to half-assing a bunch of things. House made pastries and meats, a concise but diverse menu and a levelheaded vibe will have me back at Trinket when I am in need of a breakfast I can rely on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alex</name></author><summary>I woke up this morning in my Southeast Portland bed and immediately opened up my own Portland breakfast to-do list to see where I should go next. I settled with a place called Trinket on the corner of SE Lincoln and Cesar Chavez nestled between an independent bicycle shop and a hair salon. Trinket is only open until the early afternoon so I got the feeling that they knew what they were doing when it come to breakfast.</summary></entry><entry><title>Hello, From Alex</title><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/07/13/alex-breakfast-quest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, From Alex" /><published>2016-07-13T07:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-07-13T07:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/07/13/alex-breakfast-quest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/07/13/alex-breakfast-quest/">&lt;p&gt;In the last four years that Reid, Connor and I have known each other we have eaten together countless times. From the late night munchies in our sophomore dungeon of a dorm room to indulging at restaurants that are blatantly out of our price range, it’s safe to say that our food history together is a colorful one. Our shared appreciation for well-made food always gave us something to bond over. With that in mind, a couple of weeks ago the three of us got to talking and decided we should write down our gastronomic experiences. We don’t always eat together but by sharing our stories with our readers we can open up a window into our day to day lives, whether that may be Doritos and French onion dip or Fish Sauce wings at Pok Pok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in time for us to make the blog I decided to take a trip home. By no means does that mean dreary food for me (quite the opposite actually, but that’s for another post) but it just drained my motivation to get started. So when I got back to Portland, the city’s food scene was calling my name. It was time to resume my quest to find the Portland area’s best breakfast. I am not particularly interested in crowning one as breakfast royalty, I simply want to explore the ends of the Portland breakfast world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alex</name></author><summary>In the last four years that Reid, Connor and I have known each other we have eaten together countless times. From the late night munchies in our sophomore dungeon of a dorm room to indulging at restaurants that are blatantly out of our price range, it’s safe to say that our food history together is a colorful one. Our shared appreciation for well-made food always gave us something to bond over. With that in mind, a couple of weeks ago the three of us got to talking and decided we should write down our gastronomic experiences. We don’t always eat together but by sharing our stories with our readers we can open up a window into our day to day lives, whether that may be Doritos and French onion dip or Fish Sauce wings at Pok Pok.</summary></entry><entry><title>Portage Bay</title><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/14/portage-bay/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Portage Bay" /><published>2016-06-14T07:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-14T07:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/14/portage-bay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/14/portage-bay/">&lt;p&gt;We’re like good breakfast.  Our drive back from Vancouver was no exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;portage-bay&quot;&gt;Portage Bay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way back from Vancouver, we stopped in Seattle for breakfast with some good friends.  I’m not from Seattle, but apparently this place is the place to eat breakfast if you know anything.  Personally I think the name is a little weird.  Makes me think of fish and oysters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;really-really-really-good-breakfast&quot;&gt;Really Really Really Good Breakfast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a picture of Alex’s french toast.  I had the corn beef hash.  A good way to describe these plates is this.  Anyone can make a decent breakfast.  We all have that friend who “doesn’t really eat breakfast” and thinks its the easiest meal of the day to get right.  First off, don’t be their friend.  Secondly, when you put a little time and love into it, breakfast can be absolutely spectacular.  That’s what this place was.  People who know go a little further to make breakfast that great morning sex that gets you off to an excellent day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2016-06-14-portage-bay/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img1&quot; title=&quot;french toast from portage bay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2016-06-14-portage-bay/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img2&quot; title=&quot;corn beef hash from portage bay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Reid</name></author><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Weekend trip up to Vancouver, BC</title><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/13/vancouver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekend trip up to Vancouver, BC" /><published>2016-06-13T07:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-13T07:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/13/vancouver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/13/vancouver/">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, Alex and I went up to Vancouver to visit a friend of mine and see the sights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chow&quot;&gt;Chow.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first time in Canada and first impressions were a little rocky.  First interaction with my good friend Chow the border guard, I got grilled about why my license plates were from California, but we said we were from Portland.  Then why we said we were students, but that we were also graduated.  Chow eventually gave up and handed our passports back with a dismissive “just go” after I stumbled about who the car was registered under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;subtleties-eh&quot;&gt;Subtleties, eh?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canada is like a vivid dream.  It’s like reality in a lot of ways, but there are little things that make you realize it’s not.  I’ve heard that Vancouver is like a cleaner SF or a more Asian Portland, and while I agree with that, it’s subtly different in interesting ways.  For example, driving in, I noticed Canada is a civilized country that uses the metric system.  I had no idea how fast I was going and since it wasn’t Oregon where people drive like your grandmother, I got tailgated quite a bit.  There are also a lot of streets called King-this and King-that.  No American city with any respect would do that.  There are other little things that remind you of Western Europe like people speak more than one language, and oh yeah, half of the fucking signs are in French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cars&quot;&gt;Cars.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we settled in though and had a great time.  First order of business was looking at cars.  Better than your local country club would be an understatement.  There are auto shows that don’t have as many super cars as a Saturday morning in Vancouver.  We also walked a lot.  You can google Vancouver, BC if you want to know what that was like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;french-fries-that-put-french-fries-to-shame&quot;&gt;French fries that put french fries to shame.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2016-06-13-vancouver/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img1&quot; title=&quot;french fry volcano&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our food outing of note was at Bin 941 Tapas Parlour late Saturday night where we ordered fries.  Bar fries I’ve had countless times.  But the small volcano of thinly sliced potato drizzled with balsamic and accompanied with truffle aioli couldn’t possibly share the same name as those greasy little shits we usually shove down our drunken throats on a Saturday night.  Yeah, they were good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good first trip to Canada.  Would recommend.  Especially the fries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Reid</name></author><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Coco Donuts</title><link href="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/03/coco-donuts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coco Donuts" /><published>2016-06-03T07:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-03T07:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/03/coco-donuts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://yumyuminmytumtum.com/2016/06/03/coco-donuts/">&lt;p&gt;It was nearly 100 degrees out for national donut day.  We didn’t let the heat slow us down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pro-tip-places-run-out-of-donuts-early-on-national-donut-day&quot;&gt;Pro-tip: places run out of donuts early on national donut day.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our little escapade started with a bit of a drive out to Annie’s donuts in NE way down Sandy Blvd.  Unfortunately, that place was closed.  Who eats donuts on national donut day anyways?  After failing there, we drove to one of the Coco Donuts locations in NE.  I called first to make sure they had a few donuts left.  The person working there seemed a little curious as to why the hell you would call a donut shop asking if they had donuts, but after explaining our predicament she understood.  So after another uncomfortably sweaty car ride, we finally had a donut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-chocolate-one-with-peanuts&quot;&gt;The chocolate one with peanuts.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2016-06-03-coco-donuts/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img1&quot; title=&quot;chocolate donut with peanuts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a chocolate donut with peanuts that was absolutely delicious.  Not fresh out of the oven, but paired with an iced americano (the national donut day rush cleared them out of the normal stuff) on a 100+ degree day, it was a treat.  The donuts have a little crunch to them that gives a nice texture and makes them a little more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-chocolate-one-without-peanuts&quot;&gt;The chocolate one without peanuts.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2016-06-03-coco-donuts/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img2&quot; title=&quot;connor with a chocolate donut without peanuts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was something special about the dough for this one but I’m blanking on it now.  It was also delicious.  Alex and Connor (pictured above) had one.  A classic no nonsense chocolate donut.  They don’t make them like that anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Reid</name></author><summary></summary></entry></feed>
